

Marco Antonio Orestes Teixeira

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Profile

Experienced Backend developer with great knowledge in .NET, and also able to work with Java, Javascript and Vue.Js. A team player who loves finding clever solutions to complex problems and is also open to learning new things on a daily basis. With 15+ years of experience in a variety of fields, easy to communicate and exchange experiences, great technical background, self-taught and proactive. Able to manage time and projects with ease, extensive knowledge in software development, agile methodologies and cloud services.

Employment History

Software Engineer, Agile Engine - Cardlytics, Atlanta - Georgia - USA

JUNE 2022 — PRESENT

Cardlytics is a native ad platform within banks' digital channels. They partner with top financial institutions in the US and UK to provide rewards to their customers. Over 168M bank customers help brands drive incremental sales and grow market share.

- Effectively coded software changes and alterations based on design specifications
- Enhancement and maintenance of microservices
- · Monitoring microservices statuses and health

Software Engineer, Mercado Eletrônico, São Paulo

OCTOBER 2014 — JUNE 2022

Major working with B2B platform in its maintaince and improvement. Besides that, I share my expertise, with my coworkers, guiding them in the ways of unit test, best practices, how to delivery good software and related knowledge. About the technology stack involved, I, most of the time, work with backend development like C#, Java, ASPNET Core, REST APIs, Azure services (like Blob Storage) and databases as SQLServer and MongoDB. As frontend developer, with VueJS, NodeJS (for API consuming) and Javascript or Typescript. Personally, the greatest points working there were the respect that I earned from my colleages, the capability to offer advices about software development and the active participation in most of the decisions that will change the platform.

Senior Software Developer, RDI Software, São Paulo

JANUARY 2013 — SEPTEMBER 2014

At RDI Software was my first time working for a multinational company, it was 2013, there my position was senior software developer, responsable, as a team member, to re-write and improve the POS software. As it was reaching the end of its life cycle. There I was introduced to the CI/CD cycles in software development, using TeamCity and the test driven development. That was a really nice experience and tought me a lot about how to delivery software with ease and aggregate value to every step of the development process. The achievements there was migrate the old technology to a new one (C language with socket communication to C# language with WPF (Windows Presentation Foundation) and WCF (Windows Communication Foundation)), evaluate

Details

São Paulo, Brazil +55 11 9 9291 3261 marcoaoteixeira@gmail.com

Links

<u>Linkedin</u> <u>GitHub</u>

Skills

Adaptability

Effective Time Management

Ability to Work Under Pressure

Communication Skills

Ability to Work in a Team

MySQL

Microsoft Office

Node.js

jQuery

Docker

C#

SQL

Git

JavaScript

Java

ASP.NET MVC

ASP.NET Core

REST

MongoDB

HTML/CSS/JavaScript

Amazon Web Services

databases options to the software being developed and helping improve speed and integration between the legacy system (C language) with the new one (C#), as we couldn't just replace the old software because its size and importance. It was needed to take small steps.

Software Developer, Pharmalink Online, São Paulo

JANUARY 2010 — NOVEMBER 2012

At this company I was responsable for maintaince and improvment of their B2B platform. It was my first time working with a team with more than 5 people. There I develop most of my hardskills with Microsoft technologies (ASPNET, C#, SQLServer, WCF) and soft skills like teamwork, communication, problem solving, resourcefulness, etc. Some achievements of mine were to take care of a great problem with database concurrency and performance, changing the source control system to a better one (was CVS and we change to GIT).

Education

Information Technology, Universidade Anhembi Morumbi, São Paulo - São Paulo - Brazil

JANUARY 2017 — DECEMBER 2022

MBA IT Management, Universidade Anhembi Morumbi, São Paulo - São Paulo - Brazil

MARCH 2023

About to graduate

Postgraduate - Software Architecture, Universidade Federal do Rio de Janeiro, São Paulo - São Paulo - Brazil

MARCH 2023

About to graduate

Courses

MongoDB Basics, Mongo University

JANUARY 2020 — FEBRUARY 2020

The MongoDB Aggregation Framework, Mongo University

JUNE 2021 — JULY 2021

MongoDB for .NET Developers, Mongo University

AUGUST 2021 — SEPTEMBER 2021

Microservices Architecture, Udemy

SEPTEMBER 2022 — OCTOBER 2022

SOLID Principles: Introducing Software Architecture & Design, Udemy

MAY 2022 — JUNE 2022

TDD in C#: From A to Z, Udemy

MAY 2022 — JUNE 2022

Docker: Developers' Essential Tool, Udemy

APRIL 2022 — MAY 2022

Microsoft Azure

Unit Tests

Git

RabbitMQ

VueJS

ReactJS

JIRA

TeamCity

Design Patterns

Clean Code

Kafka

Datadog

Sumologic

Languages

English (IELTS 2022 – Score 7)